Tahir Özdemir

E-mail: me [AT] tahirozdemir [DOT] com

Online Resume: cv.tahirozdemir.com

Web: me.tahirozdemir.com

Summary

I have experience in C-family languages and Python. Furthermore, I used them for robotic programming with ROS. I used MsSQL and MongoDB for database parts of my projects.

I have worked with people who were in different time-zones with a home-office system for one of my previous projects. Thus, I can say that I am suitable for both classic and home-office working style. I am currently learning Scala, Spark and some other big data tools. I always have enthusiasm for new technologies. Besides all of these I am blogging on both Medium and my domain.

Education

- 2019 - Eskişehir Osmangazi University, Computer Engineering, GPA: 3,70

Languages

- Turkish: Native

- English: Intermediate (YÖKDİL 96,25)

Experience

- Trendyol, Data Engineer, 2020-Still
- Softtech A.Ş., Software Engineer, 2019-2020
 - o I was a part of a team which develops notification systems. In this position I met some exicitng tools like Scala, Akka, Cassandra and Kafka.
- Eskişehir Osmangazi University, Developer/Researcher Intern, 2017-2019
 - o I contributed a TUBITAK project which is titled as 'Development of Autonomous Transport Vehicles and Human-Machine / Machine-Machine Interfaces for Smart Factories'. (Contact No: 116E731)
 - I was responsible for various parts of project such as solving task scheduling problem, database development, simulation etc. We used MsSQL and MongoDB for database parts. C-family languages and Python were also used for application development.

- Eskişehir Osmangazi University, Student Assistant, 2017-2018

 I have taken part as an assistant in the Introduction to Programming and Digital Systems classes. This experience gave me the ability of understanding different views on subjects.

Projects

- 'Performing Simulated Annealing Algorithm on GPU and CPU-GPU Performance Evaluation', TÜBİTAK 2209-B, 2018-2019
 - This was my final project for my bachelor's degree. The aim was solving a
 task scheduling problem with an improved version of Simulated Annealing
 Algorithm. The algorithm was developed with CUDA library and problem
 solved by GPUs.
 - Project is approved by TUBITAK and we got financial support. (Contact No: 1139B411801155)

Side/School Projects

- GitHub Markdown Editor, Go Project, 2019
 - It allows users to perform CRUD operation on markdown files in their GitHub repositories. Detailed information can be reached at <u>GitHub page</u> of the project.
- Autonomous Robot Simulation, ROS & Gazebo Project, 2017
 - This project is for Formal Languages and Automata class. It represents a simple state machine. Robotnic AGVS and Neuronics Katana Arm were used for simulation. Detailed information can be reached at <u>GitHub page</u> of the project.
- Turret Defence, Android Game (Unity), 2016
 - It is a simple tower defence game that players aim the best time. Except the
 music, all parts of it were developed by me in a week. It can be found at
 SlimeMe Market.

Conference Papers

- T. Ozdemir, A. Cibi, A. Yazici, Solution of Task Scheduling Problem for Autonomous Transfer Vehicles on GPU-CPU and Performance Evaluation [abstract], In: 3rd International Conference on Engineering And Innovation; 2019 April 17-21; Belgrade, Serbia
- A. Cibi, T. Ozdemir, I. Saricicek, A. Yazici, Scheduling of pick-up or delivery tasks for autonomous robots via dispatching rules [abstract], In: 29th European Conference On Operational Research; 2018 July 8-11; Valencia, Spain